You may have noticed
that my Instagram has been stuck on 1.4
million followers for
well over a year now. It's not budged,
and I'll tell you why.
I used to think the way to make more money
was to go more viral, and I had it
completely wrong.
Since I started aiming for less views in
my content, I've nearly
five times the amount of money
that I make.
Right here on the screen, you'll see
that my main YouTube channel so far this
year
has made me $916.
Then I have this slightly smaller channel,
and people see the
views and sometimes comment,
"Bro fell off." But so far this year,
as of the
19th of January, $162,000.
But it's not really all mine.
Got ads, the team. If you boil it down,
I think we're running at about 55%
margin. So 162 sounds amazing,
but about 71
is mine. Then my manager gets his cut.
He'll laugh right now
when he's watching this because he'll go,
"Yeah, and the
rest." Costs, podcasts, venues. But
if I actually work it down to
how much I've earned, each day,
it's about 3,700 US dollars, which is
nice. It's less sexy than the big number.
But the good news is I probably only have
to do about four or five hours a day of
work to get that. So what changed? Well,
before, I was trying to build an audience
of viewers, not buyers.
And I'm going to give you the exact
framework to how you
can do it, so you can also make millions,
even if you don't get to keep it all,
because I certainly don't get to keep it
all.
In fact, I look sometimes, I'm like,
"Where's that gone? I don't have it.
Who has it?" And it also helps a lot of
people in my mentorship make more money.
I can say grow your business,
I can help help conversions,
I can go through all of
that, but ultimately,
it's to help you make more money.
So first thing first,
is virality bad for sales? Absolutely not.
But it's not necessarily good.
And imagine for a second, boxing.
If you're just going for virality,
you're throwing a big
overhand right hook. Very rarely
is it going to hit.
What we need is a combination of different
types of content.
We need a jab, a cross, need an uppercut,
we need hooks.
We need to be hitting people from all
angles.
So we need a mixture of different types of
content.
And one way to look at this
is something called buckets.
I've mentioned before that MrBeast
is guilty of using the same buckets over
and
over. Last to leave, 24 hours in,
biggest versus smallest, most expensive
versus cheapest.
They then just change a different theme
for all of those.
Now,
when it comes to deciding what buckets
we're going to use for our content, it
should always be centric to solving
problems. Declan, give me a profession.
Video editor. Like it. Okay,
so problems are going to be editing.
So some titles of video concepts here,
how MrBeast edits his videos,
how to edit like Logan Paul,
how to improve your editing time,
how to edit less and
make more money, whatever it is. Cool.
Second one could be color grading.
Third could be edit platforms.
What else do we make content about?
Colors, editing, sound.
That's a great one.
Then the fifth one, we could say, right,
we want viral.
So we're going to do something that's
going to get loads of people to watch our
content. We could do something like,
why "Oppenheimer" was edited terribly.
We could do why Logan Paul's editor should
be fired.
We could do everyone's using CapCut wrong.
Whatever it is,
we actually aim to be viral.
And the reason being is
if we look at all of this as being an
ecosystem, this
might be the video that brings them in,
but then these can be the videos that
convert. So sometimes
when you're looking at your ecosystem of
content, every once
in a while you want an outlier
that goes viral, but only if 80%
or the majority of
your videos behind aren't geared for going
viral.
They're geared instead for converting
people to know that you are the person to
do business with.
So from a strategy already,
we need to have buckets.
So then every week,
Declan could say Monday is editing video,
Tuesday is
color grading, Wednesday
is about what platforms, what good, bad.
Thursday is about sound,
whether it be microphones, treatment, AI,
whatever, and
Friday is going to be viral. Viral Friday.
And he's going to keep an eye on things
that are trending on the internet, things
pop culture, whatever it is.
He's going to keep a note of it.
That could be his content bucket. Go on.
So in my situation now,
I've made videos in all those topics,
but I've realized every time I make a
color grading video, it just blows up,
gets
way more views.
Would it make sense for me to stay niche
in just that and then
build them up around
that rather than try and spread it out?
So you make content on everything,
but color grading just seems-
Just itself
... just seems to be the thing. Okay.
Let me think.
Yeah, to be perfectly honest, if this
was outperforming all your reels by, let's
say, 50%,
so let's say all of these get 500,
but this one gets 1,000 plus.
I would then say, right,
you're playing in the wrong bucket.
I would say...
That's a good question, that.
I would then say we need, what are the
five main topics of color grading? Okay,
so we got exposure.
White balance.
Yep.
Contrast.
Let's make this LUT,
and let's make this viral.
So then you could do all of those videos.
Then I might say for this one,
how I color grade James Smith content,
because some
people might lure them in from that.
Why Chris Williamson's podcast
is color graded wrong.
How did this movie get this feel to it?
So then you're kind of drawing things in.
So have you listened to the Ben Affleck
Matt Damon podcast on Rogan yet?
So they're a lot smarter than people
think.
And Ben Affleck's talking about the
shutter speed or the frame
speed. It'd be shutter speed-
Frame rate
... on "Saving Private Ryan"
and what they chose to give it a dramatic
effect with
all the bombs going off. Now,
that could be a clip, or that could be
something where you go,
how "Saving Private Ryan" felt so real.
And in that,
you're talking about all of these things
with the colors and the
camera settings and all those,
but you're leaning on the film,
the creator,
the edit style, whatever it is. So this
is really where I would
be happy with you aiming for virality,
only if it's a part of an ecosystem.
Because in your exposure, white balance,
contrast, and LUT content, I want a lead
magnet in all of these. Now,
the videos that are designed to go viral,
I
don't care if there's a lead magnet in it.
It'd be great if there was,
but really what we want is an end card.
Or if it was short-form content,
they're probably going to end up
following.
Or even if they don't follow,
algorithmically, if they reacted
and watched
a long amount of that viral reel,
the algorithm will go, okay, they were
interested. They watched 80% of that reel.
The next video they put out,
we're going to serve it to them.
So that could just be your occasional one.
I did that on my main YouTube channel.
But my main YouTube channel
is kind of a strange one.
I still use it at the moment,
but it does not pay the bills as you might
think. And the way we figured this out
was when we launched
Nutonic in end of 2023,
so just over two years
ago. I thought, you know what?
On this main channel,
I've been talking about Whoop,
AG1, supplements,
calling out fitness fads.
I thought those people would go, "Oh,
mate, you know what? That sounds great.
I'm ordering some." I go, "Cool.
I'll just make content for you for a few
years.
You're going to support me on my journey."
The hatred that I got, and I
realized what I'd done
is I'd actually built an audience of
people that just
love seeing people get torn down.
I hadn't built a brand.
I had built an audience of people
that wanted to see AG1 get buried
or be told why Whoop was crap.
Instead of solving people's problems,
I'd actually
just torn down businesses for virality,
and not enough of my bucket segment was
about really improving people's lives.
It might have helped some people to a
certain extent,
but I now have to appreciate
that my YouTube channel
is more for awareness than it
is operating a business like
this one.
But some people have come around where
they thought that this was just an
influencer drop. But now
if they go into Morrisons Daily in the UK,
it's part of
the meal deal.
And It's going to be rolling out into
another major supermarket
very, very soon. If you're in Texas,
it's currently in Central Markets.
Anyway,
just because that's doing a million
dollars a month doesn't mean I know
what I'm on about.
So we need to ask ourself a question.
Why are people in your existing audience
not buying yet?
Now, whenever I see this
or someone says to me in the Discord,
my business
mentorship,
"I'm having an issue with sales," first
two things I ask them is, "How
many new followers?
How many on the email list in the last 90
days?" Now, some of
you will have seen me talking about this
before.
I have a four S system where we can
determine where the bottleneck is in your
business. Socials, squeeze, sell, scale.
Now,
if you are just making content for
virality, have a look at some of the
biggest YouTube accounts out there.
They can often be incredibly heavy in
their socials,
but they haven't really taken
the stages necessary to squeeze. And
that was one of the trips I fell into
when I
was running big. 1.4 million on Instagram,
1.8 million on TikTok,
1.1 million on Facebook.
But I haven't really squeezed enough of
them.
Now, here's a framework that's very,
very important.
Between these two, 20%
is the number you want to aim for.
So if your following is 100,
you want 20 people on your email list.
If it's 10,000, you want 2,000.
Then this takes you into one of two
places.
More common than not,
you need more emails.
Nine out of 10 people need more emails,
and one out of 10 people need more
followers.
So you're either planting seeds
or you're harvesting.
And sometimes, even
if your socials take a little bit of a dip
to grow your email
list, that's the really,
really important place you need to be.
So the first reason as to why people
aren't buying your stuff is
that they're stuck
on socials.
They haven't had their data taken from
them.
Now, for instance,
if you want to really understand how to
get
that from someone,
I've actually built a completely free
course.
I'm going to put a link in the
description.
It's called Lead Magnet Mastery.
Like I said, it's completely free.
There's no hidden charges
or anything like that.
And you can get through
that in probably about 45 minutes,
and it teaches you
everything you need to do to get people's
email addresses from social media, what
you need to give them,
how to create the offer.
You can get that done as well in a day.
You could not only do the whole course,
you could create a lead magnet in a day,
which means you can start getting email
addresses from people.
A lot of people had a lot of success with
that. Highly recommend it.
Took me a long time to make.
Please enjoy it.
So the first barrier,
if your content doesn't get traction,
people aren't going to
buy stuff.
But then you can have millions
and millions of followers.
If you don't have their data,
it can be very difficult to position an
offer.
Because when you position an offer on
social media, we need to appreciate one
thing.
This circle represent your total
following.
This circle represents how many of your
following are keen to do business with
you.
So when you post about your offer on
social media, these people are interested,
but
the vast majority aren't.
So they swipe away quick,
they don't read the caption,
they move away.
That signals to the algorithm,
"This post is not good." Even
compared to their usual. It's not good,
doesn't show it to any more people.
Instead, what we want
is to be able to communicate with these
people, often via
email. That's why we do
that stage in the first place.
But then what is it
that we do to these people? Well,
we need to sell.
And selling is where the majority of
people make so many mistakes
that they're just
leaving money on the table. Now,
just before we get into sell,
some people have the
question of how much they should be
charging.
Very simply, I want you to imagine this.
These squares can represent anything.
They could be hotel rooms in a hotel
that you've built.
They could be hours in your diary,
or they could be units of energy
that you have
in a week that cannot be traded, formed,
or there's only a certain amount of energy
that any person has in a week.
When you have an empty diary
or an empty hotel and
the rooms are full, you want to be cheap,
and the reason you want to be cheap is so
that you can fill them.
And then as you start to fill up,
at this point, you still
haven't really got the leverage to
increase prices.
So you keep marketing, keep marketing,
keep marketing.
Even now, you're nearly there. Now,
at this point,
when you're nearly maxed out
from the amount of work or energy
or whatever it can, now
is where you have the
leverage to increase prices.
But ultimately, what we want to do
is we want to get
to full capacity.
When we get to full capacity,
first of all, we can send a signal
back to our email list that we are full.
When things are sold out,
it sends a signal
that a lot of people want what you are
selling, service, product, whatever it is.
And this gives us the opportunity to
create a wait list, which
is another form of
squeeze.
You are saying to people on socials, "Hey,
by the way, currently full.
Join the wait list." People
are incentivized to do that.
Even the people that aren't interested,
you might get their attention.
"Well, wow, how the hell is
that person so full?" Now,
when you increase prices,
often I say 10% is a nice amount. Now,
here's the beauty.
When you put your rates up by 10%,
all the people that love you
and value you and
cherish your services will stay.
But some people won't, and this
is actually quite
good. In all the time
that I raised prices,
I only lost one client,
Laura. I remember you, Laura.
I don't even believe you were gluten-free.
But when you put your rates up 10%,
even looking back at this,
even though you've
now cleaned up some time in your diary,
you're now earning the same money.
And what you've now done
is actually freed up four hours to do more
marketing,
where you can then make more pieces of
content and send more emails, which
eventually means that these
are going to fill up again.
Then when these fill up again,
you put your rates up by another 10%.
Now, the time between this could be weeks,
could be months, could be days, whatever
it is.
Then a couple clients drop off again.
You got two more hours where you can start
to do more on socials, more on squeeze,
and then suddenly they fill up again,
and that's going to be your life.
Not to mention, when you are busy,
if you're on the gym floor
or you've got an
accountancy firm or someone even inquires
and they say, "Hey, I want to use your
services." You go, "Sorry, I'm full.
Join the wait list." This sends people
crazy.
A bit like when people want to get a 911
GT3.
They go to the showroom,
"I'd like to order a GT3." You can't.
"I would like to buy a Rolex." You can't.
It makes them go so crazy,
they go to the gray market
and pay excess amounts of
money for it. Cool.
So that's how you determine how much you
charge.
You charge based on the amount of demand
there is for your services, nothing else.
So from the squeeze component,
let's say we've got the emails up here.
Now,
the first point of call people think
is to book people in for sales calls.
Now,
let me tell you this from my experience.
I've never done a sales call,
so maybe don't listen.
You don't want to do the sales call.
They don't want to do the sales call.
You don't want to sell for an hour.
They don't want to be sold to for an hour.
Even if your success rate is high on this,
what are you comparing it to?
Are you running a split between this
and a landing page or whatever it is?
I'm just not sure.
I have some concerns with sales calls.
First of all, empty diary effect.
If your diary's empty,
they're going to think
you're rubbish. If it's full,
they can't get a time,
and they end up leaving the
funnel and joining someone else.
A lot of people use high pressure,
and a lot of
people actually withhold information from
someone because they want to give them
the information on the call.
I'm just going to tell you a quick story.
I built a shower outside my house.
I didn't. Someone else did.
Copper shower, hot water, beautiful,
loads of pressure.
I'm out there showering in the morning.
It was supposed to be to wash
when I come back from the beach.
It's now become my number one shower.
My neighbors said,
"That's a lovely shower.
Do you mind me asking how much
that is?" I go, "Not a problem.
The issue is,
I don't know." I wanted the shower so
much, I just told the guy to
come and install it.
Didn't get an invoice for a few days.
And they said,
"Can you let us know how much it was?" I
go, "Sure.
The second I find out." I said,
"Do you want his number?" They go, "No,
no, no.
We don't want his number.
We just want to know how much it is." I
end up getting
the invoice, paid the invoice,
said to them how much it was. They go,
"Great.
We're going to get in touch." He came out
the other day, and he's going to install
a shower for them. The only thing
that helped them make a decision
was the price,
and once they found out the price,
they knew what it was, they booked.
If people don't know your prices
and you're withholding it to a call before
you
tell them,
you're going to get a lot of people
that go, "Oh my God, that's more
than I was expecting."
And they're going to waste your time.
Whereas if you just show your pricing
and be proud about it, like my business
mentorship right now is $3,500, which
is still a steal.
But I'm telling you that right now,
so those of you that can't afford that,
don't
join. That's the beauty of it.
I'm not going to wait until you're on a
high-pressure sales call,
which couldn't happen because we don't do
sales calls.
But instead,
it seems moronic to me to get people to go
through to a
sales call.
If you need to chat to someone for an hour
to think if something's good
or not, it can't be
that good What you really need to send
them to is a landing
page, and there is a certain format
that you want to use for this to work
really
well. And by the way,
if you want not only a copy of this
but a way more detailed
breakdown,
I'm going to put a link in the description
where you can just take full
advantage of this.
This has helped people make a lot more
money, and they've never
had to pay me any money to get it.
I will accept a bit of branding at the
top, but
so many people way do overkill with this.
So imagine when I land on a page,
whether mobile or desktop,
and please optimize
them for both,
because people of my generation use their
laptop.
I won't pay off my Amex unless it's on my
I don't buy stuff unless it's on my
laptop.
I don't buy plane tickets unless it's on
my laptop.
So some people fall prey to the fact
that they have such a big bit of branding
here that all I get is the heading
and subheading,
or I might just get the heading
and it just looks a bit naff.
So branding acceptable, but really
that should
be at the top. Heading, what is it?
Subheading, give me a bit more context.
Declan, give me a service, business,
something like that.
Lawn mowing. Okay,
bit of an interesting one to do online,
but let's say people
want to know how to mow their own lawns.
Yeah.
Heading,
stop wasting money on landscapers.
Stop wasting money
when you could do it yourself.
Make your lawn perfect yourself. These
are the kind of titles I'm thinking.
Then the subheading would be,
learn everything you need to know about
fertilizer,
cut lengths, mowers,
I don't know much about fucking
landscaping, et
cetera.
So that you can have the perfect lawn
without having to pay a stranger to
come round and do it for you. Better yet,
enjoy the process. Cool.
Then we would have the VSL.
My name's Dave, and I run Dave's Lawns.
Over the years,
I've worked on thousands of properties,
and there's been a problem.
That problem is,
I think most men actually want to take
care of the lawns
themselves,
not have a stranger come out
and do it for 50 pounds an hour.
So I created this program,
and this program teaches you everything
you need to know
so you can do the lawn whenever you want,
however you want.
You can get whatever type of grass,
whatever it is. Pricing.
You can join this program or this program.
Then the footer.
There is a bit more
that needs to go there,
but I'm going to save that for you guys
to download this as an asset. Again,
Dave's brand for his
logo isn't really going to be doing much
lifting up here.
The heading's going to be the best part.
And let's say you're a boxing coach.
Get boxing fit.
Train like a professional boxer.
Subheading, boxing gyms
are very intimidating, and the truth
is you can get almost
all of the results doing it from home.
This program, X, Y, Z.
VSL, tell them what it is,
tell them what they get.
And actually, there
is the format you want to get in your VSL
and actually the rest
of the page. What it is. So many people,
"Hi, my name's James.
I'm a personal trainer from..." No one
cares.
Just tell them what it is,
why they need it,
so the stranger doesn't come round and
mow their lawn and shag their wives.
What they get. Is it a course?
Is it a service? Is it one-to-one calls
or whatever? This is an interesting one.
Why to believe you. Now,
when it comes to why to believe you,
it's either
money-back guarantee, testimonials,
or both.
If you can put both of those in,
you can crush.
People in my mentorship,
they find this crazy.
They've been brainwashed into doing it
such a different way.
They can't believe that
when you give people all that information,
tell them how to
pay, and especially
if you have a money-back guarantee,
you just send people to a
website and they buy. Again,
if you get that template,
it makes your life so much
easier.
And then once you have your offer like
this, you can send
it email.
You could then even have a quiz as a
marketing funnel and
send them this.
You could even have an autoresponder
that when people DM your page,
that it sends them about it. There
are so many ways you can do this.
Not to mention, from an ads perspective,
you can retarget all the people that visit
and then don't leave.
Then you can have an abandoned cart
sequence.
Some people go through the process of
buying, then if they leave, you can
have a follow-up email sequence
and get them.
I cannot stress this to people enough.
If you can create an audience, people
that are interested in your stuff, and you
get 20% of them on email,
then you send that 20% of people this,
it's going to have
a phenomenal rate to the amount of sales
that you can make.
Let me show you in real time. Social,
you're watching this video on YouTube
right
now. Those of you
that want the landing page template
are going to be squeezed, and
I'm going to email you with more things
that you can do to your landing page.
Out of those of you that get the asset,
I'm going to sell to you.
I'm going to sell you an offer.
If you don't buy the main mentorship
and buy
something smaller,
I'm going to scale by selling you
something bigger come the end
of it. And also,
I'm going to bypass the whole thing
and give you a link to just
join my course right now. This
is me selling my shit right in plain
sight.
Because it's important for you to
understand that you can change your
audience from
viewers to buyers. I must,
at the same time,
turn this audience from viewers into
buyers. You got this for free.
Imagine what you get if you pay me.
If you learn that, you'll be fine.
As long as you do not fall into the one
trap
that a lot of people do
is thinking they need to earn $100,000 a
month in business,
because that is probably the biggest
brainwashing scam going in the whole
business
self-help guru community right now.
And if you have been led to believe
that you need to make six figures a month,
well, I need to de-brainwash you. Is
that even a thing? De-brainwash you.
If you watch this short video here,
whether you're earning 1,000, 10,000, or
50,000 a month,
you could save yourself a lot of time,
energy, and frustration.
Because if you've even just thought
that you would like to earn 100K a month,
that's going to screw you up unless you
understand this framework that I put in
this video right here. So enjoy,
and click that.